<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine-Learning on My portfolio</title>
    <link>https://codevardhan.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine-Learning on My portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:12:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://codevardhan.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EazyPredict ML module</title>
      <link>https://codevardhan.github.io/projects/2023-02-03-eazypredict-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:12:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://codevardhan.github.io/projects/2023-02-03-eazypredict-module/</guid>
      <description>EazyPredict - Running and comparing multiple ML models at once Welcome to the world of &amp;lsquo;EazyPredict&amp;rsquo;, a Python module that aims to make trying out multiple prediction algorithms as simple and efficient as possible. The module was heavily influenced by the &amp;lsquo;LazyPredict&amp;rsquo; module. I developed this module to address a few shortcomings I identified in LazyPredict.&#xA;Why EazyPredict? Some of its key features are as follows -&#xA;The &amp;lsquo;EazyPredict&amp;rsquo; module utilizes a limited number of prediction algorithms (10) in order to minimize memory usage and prevent potential issues on platforms such as Kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kNN algorithm explained intuitively!</title>
      <link>https://codevardhan.github.io/posts/2022-01-30-knn-algorithm-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 12:12:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://codevardhan.github.io/posts/2022-01-30-knn-algorithm-demystified/</guid>
      <description>In this blog we go through the kNN algorithm logic, implement it from scratch in python and apply it on the MNIST digit dataset&#xA;Prerequisites machine learning, supervised vs unsupervised ML, classification vs regression&#xA;Introduction The K Nearest Neighbour classification is a simple and efficient machine learning model that can used for classification. While there are more complex classification models, if establishing a model with some training dataset is proving troublesome, it is likely that a kNN algorithm will provide the best solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Extension To Monitor Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://codevardhan.github.io/projects/2021-05-31-notblue-chrome-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:10:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://codevardhan.github.io/projects/2021-05-31-notblue-chrome-extension/</guid>
      <description>Chrome Extension To Monitor Mental Health Introduction This project was a really interesting one that I was fortunate enough to be a part of! We made as an entry project to compete in a hackathon organised by HackOn. We did not win the hackathon, but we did create a unique and interesting project. (imo)&#xA;Our project aims to monitor a user&amp;rsquo;s search patterns and use this information to inform their close/loved ones about potential mental health problems the user might be facing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
